<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Netezza Emulator Cheats | 4LiF3h4x0r5]]></title>
  <link href="http://darkusha.com/blog/categories/netezza-emulator-cheats/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://darkusha.com/"/>
  <updated>2018-08-02T13:02:16+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://darkusha.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Denys Arkusha]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Netezza Emulator: In-Memory Run]]></title>
    <link href="http://darkusha.com/blog/2016/09/01/netezza-emulator-in-memory-run/"/>
    <updated>2016-09-01T15:18:29+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://darkusha.com/blog/2016/09/01/netezza-emulator-in-memory-run</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I want two share some experience that I&rsquo;ve got some time ago on the Netezza related testing.<br/>
This article is not just around Netezza emulator, but the approach described below allowed me
to save a lot of time on testing within I/O-greedy configurations (the laptop was just equipped by slow IDE HDD but with 16 GB of RAM).</p>

<p>The problem I&rsquo;ve faced was very slow performance of test SQL statements execution and I assumed that
using of RAM Disk approach hypothetically could help me.</p>

<h4>Starting from that point I planned to accomplish the following steps:</h4>

<ul>
<li>Find and Setup the RAM Disk for Windows software (I&rsquo;m sure there are kind of alternatives are available for other platforms)</li>
<li>Setup it</li>
<li>Place the Netezza VM into the virtual disk and spin it in RAM</li>
<li>Get the performance profit :)</li>
</ul>


<h4>The progress and the pitfalls:</h4>

<ul>
<li>I&rsquo;ve chosen the <a href="https://www.softperfect.com/products/ramdisk/">SoftPerfect RAMDisk</a> as a software and it was really perfect.
It&rsquo;s useful and intuitive from installation and using perspectives.</li>
</ul>


<p><img src="https://www.softperfect.com/products/ramdisk/scr_main_window.png" alt="SoftPerfect RAMDisk UI" /></p>

<ul>
<li>I&rsquo;ve placed the VM image into the newly created RAM folder (8GB). <code>!Pitfall is there! When I didn't get expected performance boost, I've just installed the VMPlayer into the RAM folder as well as the VM image I've copied into it.</code></li>
<li>Started VMPlayer newly installed into RAMDisk</li>
<li>Started Netezza VM&hellip;</li>
</ul>


<h3>Viola! My Netezza VM start working 10 times faster</h3>

<p>(on my own hardware of course :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
